Kenneth Ekandem

For a start, I am a Javascript and PHP backend developer with 4+ years experience in building, testing, debugging and deploying web applications. Effective in server setup, database maintenance and structuring. A team leader who can work as a team player and effective at delivery of projects.

123 Your Street
Your City, ST 12345
+234 09 6717 0010
kennyekandem@gmail.com
https://kennethekandem.netl
ify.app

EXPERIENCE

LogRocket, Remote — *Article Writer*

November 2020 - PRESENT

As a developer, I wanted to share my experience and getting the position as an article writer was a big step. In the role, I have written a couple of articles that have impacted developers, helped solved a problem and detailed explanation on a topic. I cover topics which range from caching (Redis for the most part), authentication, APIs creation and effective use of different databases and also detailed how-to topics.

Codekago Interactive, Akwa Ibom State — Lead Backend Developer

January 2020 - PRESENT

With the position of lead developer came great responsibilities. I was in-charge of configuring servers, structuring databases, choosing the best backend stack for a specific project, creating and implementing user stories in relation to the backend and server maintenance for old projects. As Lead developer I've seen the completion of 5 Major projects which had large user base and were extended to mobile applications.

Codekago Interactive, Akwa Ibom State — Backend Developer

January 2019 - December 2019

On my return to Codekago Interactive as a Backend developer, I joined the core team in building live applications which have a user base ranging to the thousands and that gave me a sense of carefulness and security on how to go about my building applications which impacted so many lives. I saw the rebuild of most of the company's applications and launch of postponed or abandoned ones.

Codekago Interactive, Akwa Ibom State — *Paid Intern Developer*

May 2017 - May 2018

As an intern developer at Codekago, I got the opportunity to learn a lot in regards to programming, got hands on live projects and worked first hand

SKILLS

Javascript (Node.js, AdonisJs, ExpressJs, NuxtJs, NextJs)

PHP (Laravel, Lumen, Sanctum)

Database / Language (MongoDB, MySQL, GraphQL, SQLite, Firebase)

Hosting (Cpanel, DigitalOcean, Heroku, Netlify)

Links

Twitter:

https://twitter.com/Kenneth Ekandem

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ kenneth-ekandem-66a73a116 /

Github:

https://github.com/Kennethekandem

LogRocket:

https://blog.logrocket.com/au thor/kennethekandem/

LANGUAGES

PHP, Javascript

with team members which helped improve my communication skills.

EDUCATION

University of Uyo, Akwa Ibom — *Bs.c*

September 2019

PROJECTS

Protraka — Diesel tracking

Protraka is a phenomenal web application which allows consumers to buy and keep track of their diesel consumption. It also allows for sellers to put diesel up for sale and consumers could bargain prices in real-time.

<u>OakExpress</u> — Logistics services

OakExpress is a logistic company with quick and effective delivery service. To better render their service, a mobile application which supports both android and iOS devices was built and deployed along with a web application for better accessibility purposes.

ManageAm — Diabetics Tracker

ManageAm is a mobile and web based application which keeps track of diabetic patients, gives them tips on how to stay healthy and tracks their food and calories consumption. It also recommends and tracks drug use and educates users on how to deal with diabetes.

Passward — Ecommerce

Passward is an ecommerce website with vendors, agents and sellers in mind. With Passward, a vendor can put their products up for sale, and an agent can manage the online store for the vendor while a user can shop nonstop with zero inconveniences.